# **Ivan Symchych**

Software Engineer from Lviv, Ukraine

Email: ivan.symchych@gmail.com

Github: isymchych

LinkedIn: ivansymchych

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack software developer with 11 years of experience, seeking interesting projects. I can build projects from the ground-up, and develop them without accumulating too much technical debt.

A systems thinker, pragmatic, result-oriented. I enjoy finding simple solutions to complicated problems. Know about clean code, teamwork, documentation, and tests.

Committed to professional growth.

Not interested in gambling, bets, surveillance, or ads industries.

#### **TECHNICAL HIGHLIGHTS**

- TypeScript, JavaScript, Rust, Java, SQL, GraphQL
- HTML, CSS, SCSS, CSS-in-JS
- OOP/OOD, FP, Design Patterns, SOLID, HTTP, REST
- Linux, Emacs, Jenkins, Docker

I'm an expert in **TypeScript** and **JavaScript**, love and enjoy **Rust**, and, earlier in my career, used to code in **Java**.

Last few years I was working primarily with React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, GraphQL, REST, HTML, SCSS, CSS-in-JS, and a bit of Angular.

Also, I have experience with HTML5 video streaming and WebRTC.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Contractor at Remit April 2016 - February 2021

## • Web Frontend for MaginePro, a video streaming company

MaginePro is a white-label OTT platform. I helped to build the single-page application in React and prerendering server in Node.js. Application is highly customizable via feature flags and scales for multiple partners, which could be configured on the fly.

Also, I was working on a cross-platform video player, Chromecast receiver application, introduced end-to-end tests, and automated internal processes.

JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux.js, Node.js, Fela, GraphQL

## • Calendar application for ThinkTank, the platform for collective intelligence

Single page calendar application for managing events and appointments using REST API in Java. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, SASS, Java, Spring

### Contractor at SoftServe August 2015 - April 2016

#### • Jitsi Meet for Atlassian

I was refactoring and fixing bugs in the Jitsi.org web app, an open-source video conferencing solution. JavaScript, Babel, Lodash, JQuery

#### • HipChat for Atlassian

I was working on React-based web UI for HipChat, a chat for teams from Atlassian. I took part in refactoring, bugfixing, and writing unit and integration tests.

JavaScript, React.js, Babel, Lodash, Karma, Selenium

#### Full stack (Java/JavaScript) developer at Intellias July 2012 - August 2015

#### Secure online chat peer.me for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

Webchat leverages the power of WebRTC, cutting-edge technology which allows browsers to communicate with each other without a server (peer-to-peer), with end-to-end encryption. I was working on the library which encapsulates core functionality like sending encrypted text messages and files, synchronizing data between clients, establishing group audio and video calls. Also, I took part in the development of SPA UI and backend.

Java, WebSockets, WebRTC, Marionette.js, Tomcat, Jasmine

## Web portal and utilities for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

The web portal is a SPA for customers to manage their phone numbers, routing plans, bills, calls forwarding, etc., and an admin portal to manage customers and internal business processes. The backend was implemented as a REST API. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Marionette.js, Bootstrap

#### • Web portal for RPLab, diagnostic laboratory from Belgium

Web frontend for ETL process on client medical data. As a result, the system also generates per-client reports in HTML or pdf formats. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, MongoDB, JSP, Stripes, FlyingSaucer, JFreeChart

## Java Developer at JSC Kredobank July 2010 - July 2012

#### Web services to aggregate and simplify internal business processes

I was working on design, development, bugfixing, and support of internal web services. Also, I built a GUI client in Swing for those web services.

Java, JBoss, SOAP, WSDL, Oracle 11g, Jenkins CI, Gradle

#### **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics, Ivan Franko National University Of Lviv, Ukraine, 2007 - 2013

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Advanced **Ukrainian** Native

Russian Limited working proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

programming, science fiction & popular science, traveling, hiking, computer games